Welcome to our training on return reports.
It's wonderful when customers love the products they buy,
but sometimes a customer opens a box to find that the product just isn't right for them.
When that happens, they may decide to return it.
Keeping track of which products are returned
and when is an important part of your business.
You can use our return reports feature to monitor
customer returns and generate records.
To access your return reports, open the Seller Central Main
menu, hover over Reports and click Return Reports.
On the Return Reports page, you can track your
history of returns by generating reports on demand or by scheduling them on a regular basis.
Your first option is to generate a one-time report.
To do this, start by selecting whether
you'd like a report for all returns or only prime returns.
Then select the time period that you'd
like the report to cover.
If you select exact dates, you'll then need to select the date range
you want the report to cover.
Once you've made your choices, select Request.
Once you request a
report, you'll see a notice that the report is in progress.
Your request will appear under Generated
Reports.
How long it takes to create the report will depend on the number of returns in that report's
date range.
Select Refresh to check on the report's status.
If there were returns during that period,
you'll receive links to an XML file and a TSV file.
XML stands for the Extensible Markup Language,
while a TSV file is a tab-separated values file.
Most commercial spreadsheet applications can
open TSV files.
If you want to schedule a regular report, select Schedule Report Generation.
Here, you can generate three different types of reports.
Reports for exemptions,
reports for all returns, and reports for prime returns.
Select how often you'd like to receive
any of the report choices, and then select Schedule next to that option.
If you have a report scheduled,
you'll see the date when the next report will be generated, as well as options to reschedule
or unschedule a report.
Rescheduling a report will change the report timing, while unscheduling
a report stops it from being automatically generated.
When a scheduled report is created,
you can find it under generated reports on the return reports page.
When you open a return report,
you'll see information about every return that meets the criteria you chose.
You can see the
order ID, the order date, the date the return was requested, and the return status.
The next set
of columns provides information about the return label and how it was shipped.
For more information
about return labels, search for prepaid returns and returnless resolutions in Seller Central.
You'll also find information about whether the return was the result of an A-Z guarantee claim,
or was a prime order, as well as information about the product itself, how many were returned,
and why they were returned.
This information is important to helping you monitor your inventory.
If you see many orders of the same product returned for the same reason,
check your product and its listing to make sure there aren't any problems.
You may be able to catch these before they impact your account health.
The next set of columns show whether your return is related to SAFE-T claims.
SAFE-T
stands for Seller Assurance for E-Commerce Transactions.
A seller might make a SAFE-T claim if Amazon
processes a return on the seller's behalf, but certain conditions are met that show the seller
isn't responsible for the return.
To learn more about SAFE-T claims, search for "SAFE-T claim"
in the Seller Central search bar.
In the very last column, you can see the amount
refunded to customers for each return.
If you sell products using fulfillment by Amazon or FBA,
there are other reports specific to FBA sellers.
To access them, click "View FBA Reports" near the
top of the return reports page.
This concludes our training on return reports.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.